# **Andrew Neidley**

Software Developer <a href="http://andrewneidley.com">http://andrewneidley.com</a>

### aneidley@gmail.com

903-748-8898 linkedin.com/in/andrewneidley github.com/Neidley

# **Summary**

I am a certified full-stack software developer and Austin AngelHack Global Hackathon winner with 10 years of customer service and management experience.

My strengths are Frontend Development, Debugging, and Technical Communication in Ruby on Rails and various JavaScript frameworks.

Also...lifelong video gamer, alt music fan and ACL festival frequenter, and I cook a mean chili that is great for all occasions!

# **Skills**

#### LANGUAGES:

JavaScript, Ruby, HTML, CSS

# FRAMEWORKS/LIBRARIES:

Ruby on Rails, JQuery, React, AngularJS

### CSS

Bootstrap, CSS3, CSS Grid

### DATABASE/STORAGE:

PostgreSQL, SQLite, SQL, Firebase, AWS S3

### ADDITIONAL SKILLS:

Test Driven Development, RESTful APIs, GitHub

# **Employment History**

AT&T Wireless Texarkana, TX | 06/2013 - 03/2017 Retail Sales Consultant promoted to Assistant Store Manager

Best Buy Texarkana, TX | 01/2010 - 06/2013 Home Theater Specialist promoted to Department(s) Lead

Regal Cinemas Harrisonburg, VA | 03/2007 - 12/2009 Floor Staff promoted to Assistant Manager

# **Projects**

### Landmark Discoveries |

https://landmark-discoveries.herokuapp.com/users/sign\_up

- Encourages users to learn more about historical landmarks they pass. You can identify a landmark just by taking a picture of it thanks to the Google Vision APII
- Storage with PostgreSQL and AWS S3 buckets and the Ruby Paperclip gem for image uploading.
- Uses Ruby on Rails full-stack for RESTful API Routing.

### Magmapedia |

# https://magmapedia.herokuapp.com/users/sign\_up

- Standard Users have the ability to contribute to and create public wikis while Premium users can create private wikis and add contributors.
- Ruby on Rails based web app utilizing a number of gems including Devise for Authentication, Stripe for payment to premium membership, and Figaro for Rails configuration for Heroku deployment to production.

# Space Chat |

# https://neidley-space-chat.herokuapp.com

- Do, or do not use Space Chat to discuss popular Science Fiction with friends. There is no try.
- Built with Angular and Firebase's database and authentication systems.
- Space Chat allows users to create chat rooms and quote popular Sci-Fi references.

# Education

Bloc | 04/2017 - 10/2018

Software Development Certification

- 13 projects in 18 months covering the skills listed below
- Over 75 hours of side-by-side, pair-programming with senior developers.

# Curriculum Covered:

- Front-end Development (Command Line, Github, JS, JQuery, HTML, CSS, Angular Framework)
- Back-end Development (Ruby, Ruby on Rails Framework, Databases Postgres, Firebase, and SQL)
- Software Engineering Principles (Algorithms, Data Structures, Relational Database Fundamentals)
- Open Source Apprenticeship (create your own project and contribute to existing projects)
- Certified and Graduate as of October 15th, 2018